After
you've shared the service, I kindly
request that you can be upstanding for
the reading of God's word.
I continue my sermon from last Sunday.
My text is Proverbs chapter 22 29.
Proverbs 22
29.
I think by now if you've been to this
church, you would be able to define what
Proverbs is all about and what Psalms
is.
It's so easy to define what the Psalms
are because the Psalms and the Proverbs
actually you just have to remember the
cross and remember that the Psalms have
to do with our vertical relationship
with God and proverbs has to do with the
horizontal relationship with people and
how to relate with people that you find
yourself in this earth with. So the book
of Psalm basically talks about our
relationship and our worship, our
adoration to the living God. But when it
comes to proverbs, it gives you the
wisdom for living. Somebody say wisdom
for living.
So the book of proverbs, we are in
there. I hope you've turned there.
Proverbs chapter 22 and verse 29.
A scripture says, do you see a man who
excels
in his work?
He will stand before kings.
That means that person is going to be
valuable. He's going to be in demand.
He will be sought after
not just by mere men. He will not stand
before unknown men. Father, in the name
of Jesus, thank you for the reading of
your word. Bless it to our hearts.
May we glean some wisdom from this text
today, Lord God Almighty.
be glorified Lord in the preaching and
the teaching of your word and I pray
Lord Jesus Christ that heaven will
rejoice and that uh Satan will be
horrified. Thank you father for this
wonderful opportunity that you've given
us this morning. Receive the praise and
the glory. Somebody say amen.
>> Amen.
>> You may be seated in the presence of the
Lord.
In this life you will have a lot of
people who want access to you.
You will interact with all sorts of
people in this life.
The tall, the short,
beautiful, the ugly.
All sorts of people want access to you.
But very few people
bring
value,
substance
to you.
And if you're a person of value, you
will be shocked at the amount of people
who are just empty.
People who are just
there.
They are not deep in their thinking.
They're not deep in their rationale.
They are
people that come and just waste your
time.
As I was growing up, I was taught and I
of course uh being a pastor, being a
reverend, being a bishop,
I was coached by some of the best in the
world.
And if you're not careful, even as a
bishop, one of the things that you
encounter is time wasters.
uh people who want to see you for the
sake of seeing you, you know. You see,
the anointing is attractive.
You have to understand that
uh you may not be handsome, but if
you're anointed, you'll be attractive.
Uh I normally tell people, let me not
even go there. Let me I can say so many
things about that. But anyways, praise
the Lord. Amen.
My secretary is trained
I took the time in fact uh one time I
was in London and uh I was uh preaching
for my friend Dr. Albert and he had a
fantastic secretary,
a PA.
I was so impressed
by how she conducted that office and how
she ran that office because she ran it
with military precision as RB would tell
you
and with excellence
and uh so I thought well when I come
back to Kenya I'll tell my PA that time
it was Angel I told I I told Angel get
your visa make sure you get everything
ready we will sponsor you to go to the
UK uh for a month or so be with this
lady I can't even remember her name is a
while back
just to know how to be trained well she
didn't get the visa so when she didn't
get the visa we arranged for the lady to
come here
where there's a wheel
there's always a way so she came here
spent some time with angel and one of
the things that angel picked from her is
that people who come to see bishop David
Morathy okay should not spend more than
30 minutes
And that if you come to my office, you
spend more than 30 minutes, angel will
come and knock the door and tell you,
sir, your next appointment is waiting
for you. So that you cut your many many
stories, you know, uh and time wasting
because honestly speaking, if you can't
tell me what you came to tell me in 30
minutes, you cannot tell me in 30 hours.
BUT THEN YOU COME TO EXPERIENCE HOW
people
want access to you. Particularly if you
are a public person and particularly if
you're a successful person, particularly
if you are a successful business person.
You'll find a trail of people rushing
and wanting to be with you, wanting
maybe to have lunch and dinner or maybe
wanting to call you or maybe wanting
just to text you and you know. But the
thing about it is uh what do they bring
uh when they have access to you and
you'll be shocked at how empty most
people ARE AND HOW WE HAVE SO MANY time
wasters. PEOPLE WHO DON'T HAVE
SUBSTANCE.
AND SO EVERY SUCCESSFUL person
has mastered the arts
of knowing who's a time waster
and who is somebody of substance and who
is somebody of value. I am telling you
the truth. If you see anybody who is
successful, be it in business, be it a
bishop, be whatever it is, but they're
successful in what they're doing, they
have mastered the art of being able TO
DISTINGUISH THIS PERSON WHO'S COMING TO
ME, WHAT ARE THEY bringing into me?
BECAUSE SUCCESSFUL people are repelled
by time wasters, people who talk too
much and have no substance. And people
and by the way let me tell you being
loud is not being sound.
So I WANT TO ASK YOU THIS MORNING, HAVE
YOU GOTTEN TO THAT PLACE where you're
able to distinguish people and put them
in THEIR DIFFERENT BOXES? LOOK AT YOUR
NEIGHBOR, TELL THEM, PUT people in their
different boxes.
I feel like I'm going to preach this
morning. By the way, I just want to warn
you. I I woke up in the on the right
side, you know, of the bed. Come on,
somebody. Amen.
I woke up on the right side of the bed
today. Sometimes, you know, I I wake up
on the wrong side of the bed, but today
I woke up on the right side of the bed.
Have you ever
GOTTEN TO THAT STAGE UH WHERE YOU KNOW
YOU KNOW IF YOU RECEIVE A PHONE CALL
WHAT SORT OF PHONE call it's going to
be?
Yeah. Have you gotten to that place
where when you receive a phone call uh
you know very well uh this is an
important call or this is a time waste
because uh so many people uh in the
world have not taken time to be people
uh who carry weight to be people uh WHO
CARRY CAB TO BE PEOPLE uh who carry
substance uh uh yeah and I'm telling you
this morning uh that uh if you're going
to be a person in in this world that
will be remembered. You have to be a
person of value. And to be able to be a
to be a person of value, brothers and
sisters, ladies and gentlemen, I started
this message last Sunday. I'm going to
touch on some points quickly so I can
move on to the other one just for the
purposes of recapping. BUT IF YOU'RE
GOING TO be a PERSON OF SUBSTANCE, ONE
OF THE VERY VERY valuable things and I
think I didn't do justice to this point
is that you've got to be something that
you you've got to be somebody who brings
something into the world. LET ME ASK
YOU, WHAT IS IT THAT YOU DO?
WHAT IS IT THAT YOU'RE DOING? WHAT IS IT
THAT YOU'RE adding to me? And I'm not
talking about just me. I'm just talking
generally speaking and using me just for
these PURPOSES OF THIS ARGUMENT. WHAT IS
IT THAT WHEN I SEE YOU, I can see that
you're bringing substance TO ME. YOU'RE
ADDING value to me. UH YOU'RE SORTING A
solution to me. you're bringing answers
to where THERE ARE QUESTIONS. BECAUSE TO
BE HONEST WITH YOU, IF YOU'RE NOT
BRINGING ANSWERS TO WHERE THERE ARE
QUESTIONS, YOU ARE JUST wasting my time.
AND THERE IS NO WAY YOU CAN BE A
VALUABLE PERSON IF you're not solving
some problems.
YOUR WORK CANNOT JUST BE EATING UGALI
AND SCUMIKI.
WHAT ARE YOU SORTING IN THIS WORLD? WHAT
ARE YOU SOLVING UH IN THIS? WHAT IS WHAT
ARE YOU SOLVING? OH, I CAN JUST GO HOME
WITH THAT POINT ALONE. NOW, LOOK AT YOUR
NEIGHBOR THIS MORNING AND ASK, WHAT IS
IT THAT YOU'RE SOLVING IN THIS WORLD?
ARE YOU JUST A GOSSIPER? ARE YOU THE ONE
WHO'S TALKING WHO'S SLEEPING WITH WHO
AND WHO'S THE BIG DADDY AND WHO'S THE
SUGAR DADDY AND WHATEVER THAT IS WHAT
YOU LIVE IN. COME ON, SAM. ARE YOU WHAT?
WHAT IS IT? OH, COME ON, CHURCH. WHAT IS
IT THAT YOU'RE SOLVING IN THIS WORLD
APART FROM GLASS
FOR YOU TO BE A VALUABLE PERSON?
YOU HAVE TO BE A PROBLEM SOLVER.
AND I WANT TO SAY SOMETHING HERE THAT IS
GOING TO SHOCK YOU. YOU CAN PRAY UNTIL
YOU BECOME THIN LIKE A RAZOR BLADE. IF
YOU'RE NOT SOLVING ANY PROBLEM, YOU
WON'T GET MONEY.
CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST, LISTEN TO ME.
OH, I'M annoyed this morning. You can
tell. YOU CAN PRAY,
OKAY, AND BECOME THIN AS A RAZOR BLADE,
BUT YOU'RE GOING TO BE PAID AND YOU'RE
GOING TO BE REWARDED IN KEEPING WITH THE
PROBLEMS THAT YOU'RE SOLVING. WHAT IS IT
THAT YOU'RE SOLVING? BECAUSE I'M TALKING
ABOUT BEING VALUABLE. WHY ARE YOU
VALUABLE? WHAT ARE YOU DOING SO I CAN
CALL YOU VALUABLE?
Studed this on uh the resurrection
Sunday teaching you and showing you how
Jesus Christ came and uh if you're not
moving uh to the next dimension uh if
you're not moving uh to the next
PARADIGM UH THE DEATH AND THE
RESURRECTION OF JESUS CHRIST BECOMES A
WASTE OF TIME.
IT BECOMES A WASTE OF TIME.
UNFORTUNATELY,
a lot of people
don't carry value.
They don't carry value.
Just sit down and listen.
And you wonder, is there ANYTHING ELSE
YOU CAN TALK about apart from talking
about people? IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE?
AND BY THE WAY, I HEARD it being said
that small minds discuss people.
Big minds discuss ideas
and greater minds discuss vision.
Hallelujah.
Look at your circles. Even as I begin to
teach and to preach about this thing of
becoming valuable person because to be
able to be valuable uh oh yeah the
scripture SAYS
THOU A man who excels IN HIS WORK HE
WILL STAND BEFORE KINGS
AH KING OF GLORY help me preach this and
that IT DOES NOT MATTER WHERE YOU ARE IF
YOU'RE SOLVING SOME SERIOUS PROBLEMS
EVEN IF THERE'S NO ROAD THEY ARE GOING
TO CREATE A ROAD TO YOU SOMEBODY SAY
AMEN. OH, BISHOP DAVID OIPO TOLD US HE
WENT TO THE FOREST, STARTED A CHURCH
WHERE THERE WERE NO ROADS, NO NOTHING.
BUT BECAUSE HE CARRIED THE ANOINTING,
PEOPLE MADE THEIR WAY TO THE CHURCH. LET
ME TELL YOU SOMETHING. UH, WHEN YOU
BEGIN TO SOLVE PROBLEMS, PEOPLE WILL
MAKE THEIR WAY TO YOU. UH, PEOPLE WILL
CALL YOU. THE REASON WHY THEY'RE NOT
CALLING YOU IS BECAUSE YOU'RE EMPTY.
YOU'RE EMPTY. YOU'RE NOT SOLVING ANY
PROBLEM. WHY SHOULD YOU I CALL YOU FOR
WHAT?
Look at your neighbor said, "Do you
still want to listen to this message?"
What I'm trying to tell you church is
that you've got to be able in this world
as you continue to eat your gal and your
chapati to do more than that and to
solve problems and to be a solution. Uh
because you have something you can do UH
THERE IS A TALENT YOU CARRY. THERE IS a
skill you know and that when you get to
do what you're doing uh no one can do IT
LIKE YOU BECAUSE YOU ANOINTED for that
particular thing and that they have to
look for you. They have to MAKE A ROAD
WHERE YOU ARE BECAUSE YOU'VE GOT A SKILL
THAT YOU CARRY. YOU HAVE GOT AN
ANOINTING THAT YOU CARRY LIKE NO OTHER.
COME ON SOMEBODY GIVE YOUR NEIGHBOR HIGH
FIVE AND TELL THEM YOU HAVE TO HAVE A
SKILL. YOU HAVE TO HAVE A TALENT. YOU
HAVE TO HAVE A GIFT. YOU HAVE TO HAVE
SOMETHING THAT YOU'RE OFFERING. HOW DO
YOU BECOME VALUABLE AND YOU'RE NOT
SORTING ANYTHING IN THIS WORLD?
I was talking to friend of mine. He has
got a beautiful place
there.
And what what is that place
where you have a shamba?
Before you go to you get what is it
called? There's a beautiful place there.
Huh?
Between konabarid and there's a place
where mongus are bought homes. What
mean?
So
I was talking to him
and he asked me bishop how come uh you
know I meet with people you know he's a
carpenter
he's a German he's a fantastic carpenter
fantastic
excellent
carpenter he says I meet with people in
these Kenyans I don't understand and
every time you go to a function people
don't introduce themselves and you know
when they introduce themselves you know
what do you do that's that's the second
My name is David. What do you do? That's
the next thing that follows normally
so that they can know where to place
you.
All right.
So the guy told me, the German friend
told me, you know, I've met so many
Kenyans and I've never met a Kenyan who
introduces themsself as a carpenter.
He said, I've never met anybody who
says, you know, I'm a plumber.
go to state house where the state
functions you know or big functions you
whatever it could be and find somebody
and say hi how are you doing say oh you
know uh I'm a plumber
and then he told me you know do they
realize how important it is to be a
carpenter
do THEY REALIZE HOW IMPORTANT IT IS TO
BE A PLUMBER BECAUSE RIGHT NOW I'M
TALKING THERE IS A SCARCITY OF PLUMBERS
RIGHT NOW I'M TALKING THERE IS A
SCARCITY OF CARPENTERS.
THE CARPENTER THAT WORKS FOR ME IS FROM
TANZANIA.
ME, Bishop David Mory, he's from
Tanzania. GOOD CARPENTER. WHY? YOU GUYS
ABOLISH ALL THE TECHNICAL COLLEGES, POLY
TECHCHNICS AND EVERYTHING. YOU ABOLISH
THEM, TURN THEM TO UNIVERSITY. THERE IS
NOBODY TO DO THESE WORKS AND WE NEED
PLUMBING, WE NEED CARPENTRY, WE NEED
DRAWERS, we need, YOU KNOW, ALL THESE
THINGS IN THE HOME SO THAT THE HOME CAN
BE COMPLETE. HE SAID WHY IS IT WHY ARE
THEY ASHAMED TO INTRODUCE THEMSELVES I
AM A PROUD
carpenter
should take you to that it's called
champagne ridge
and
I should take you
show you what he has built
people go to homes he has built with
wood
pay an arm and a leg you will have to
took months to have access to that
place.
A carpenter, he's solving a problem.
HE'S SOLVING A SITUATION.
He's valuable.
He's in demand. YOU CAN GET HIM. YOU
HAVE TO BOOK.
What skill?
What talent,
what problem are you solving? For you to
be valuable, there must be something
you're sorting.
I spoke about this thing. I'm going to
very I've really preached that one
because I really wanted to get that. But
I want to move f forward. I spoke about
changing your mind and stuff. I talked
about being consistent. I talked about
being uh predictable, you know, but let
me go on
and teach you about the ground which
you're in makes you valuable.
The ground which you're in.
Yesterday I was listening to Ellen Musk,
one of my favorite people nowadays to
listen to
and he was talking about how uh people
keep on asking what is the secret of
being a billionaire in US dollars
and he stood up and spoke in this
conference and said uh I will not give
you 10 steps to become a billionaire.
I'll not give you 10 steps. I'll not do
that. But I'll tell you what my mother
taught me when I was growing up. And he
said, "My mother told me that whatever
you do, please make sure that you do it
in such a way that your name is on it."
In fact, he said, "Do it in such a way
that your signature." That means that
whatever you do, people should know
you're the one who did it. And if you
want your name to be identified with
poor or excellent, you choose
whatever you do. and said, he said,
"Well, I I learned from my mother that
whatever I do, my name is on it." He
said, "No, we try to go to the moon, it
came down. My name was on it." I lay on
the floor for days because Ellen Musk
had flopped. IT WAS NOT THAT SPACESHIP
that flopped. It was me that flopped. He
said he went down for days when he his
company ACTUALLY WENT ALMOST BEING
BROKE. ACTUALLY, they were broke. THEY
WERE BEING SOLD OUT. IT WAS ALEN MUSK
WAS BEING SOLD OUT. And he said, "I am
going to give you what my mother GAVE ME
THAT WHATEVER I DO, MY NAME IS ON IT."
Come on, somebody look at somebody this
morning and say, "WHATEVER YOU DO, YOUR
NAME IS ON IT." THAT WAS JUST A FREE
STORY. BUT THE STORY IS THIS. HE WAS IN
SOUTH AFRICA AS A SMALL BOY. THERE IS NO
WAY HE WOULD HAVE ACHIEVED WHAT he has
ACHIEVED IF HE STILL WAS IN SOUTH
AFRICA. HE HAD TO MOVE THE GROUND. AND I
CAME TO TELL YOU ENVIRONMENT IS A BIG
THING IN YOUR SUCCESS. WHICH ENVIRONMENT
DO YOU OPERATE IN IF ALON MUSK CONTINUED
BEING IN SOUTH AFRICA? THERE IS NO WAY
YOU WOULD HAVE HEARD OF HIM. HE HAD TO
MOVE TO AN ENVIRONMENT.
And so I TELL YOU THIS MORNING,
you too need to move to an environment
WHERE THERE'S GROWTH. YOU TOO NEED TO RE
TO MOVE TO AN ENVIRONMENT where you
appreciated and valued and what WOULD
YOU DO IS TAKEN SERIOUSLY. HE WOULD HAVE
DONE ALL HE did in South Africa. It
could never have hit the Newsweek,
the Time magazine
and the world.
Never
environment
fertile ground helps for you to
germinate, helps for YOU TO FLOURISH,
HELPS FOR YOU TO GROW, HELPS FOR YOU TO
HAVE IMPACT. OH YES. CAN YOU IMAGINE IF
I WAS PREACHING in Kinang?
And there's nothing wrong with Kinagop.
Nothing wrong.
Nothing wrong. Don't get me wrong. You
can't compare me preaching in Kinangop
the way I am me. Somebody else will
succeed there. Are you hearing me?
Somebody else will do very well. They'll
preach in Kikuyu. Me my Kikuyu is just
wasting water.
We went for a mission
deep deep deep. Some those days when
people are I think it was about hunger
and what have you taking food with Elusi
and the rest. It was a
I don't know if uh second lady was
there. Are you there? We went there and
then because I'm a pastor, they said,
"Okay, uh
like is good nowadays." My friend, I
spoke until it got finished.
Environment.
Are you listening to me? Environment.
Come. Come on, tell somebody.
Environment. It's not THAT YOU'RE BAD.
IT'S NOT THAT YOU'RE NOT THE right seed.
It's not that you don't have WHAT IT
TAKES, BUT ENVIRONMENT. ENVIRONMENT.
Even today, if I was to go to start a
church in Nakuru with those interior
places on the Bibi where I have a farm,
LET ME TELL YOU, I WILL NOT PREACH THE
WAY I'M PREACHING TO YOU BECAUSE OF
ENVIRONMENT. YOU'VE GOT TO CHOOSE. OH,
GOD. YOU'VE GOT TO CHOOSE YOUR
ENVIRONMENT SO THAT YOU CAN BE ABLE TO
BE VALUABLE. SAME MAN, SAME CONTENT, BUT
THE ENVIRONMENT MAKES ALL THE
DIFFERENCE. ARE YOU LISTENING TO WHAT
I'M TELLING YOU THIS MORNING? ENVIR
WHICH ENVIRONMENT
HAVE YOU CHOSEN IN ORDER TO BE VALUABLE?
ENVIRONMENT.
BUT THEN IF YOU'RE GOING TO BE VALUABLE,
my brothers and sisters,
you've got to
be a person who is known for something.
What is your brand?
Matthew chapter 5 and 16 says, "Let your
light so shine before men."
Let your light so shine. What is it that
you are known for? What is your
reputation? Uh what is your message?
When I look at you, what is your
message?
Oh, because you want to be valuable.
When you are looking for somebody who
was going to do this uh stage, we look
for somebody who has a reputation of
making altars. So when he was brought to
me, I asked him, "How many altars have
you made?" He went through the catalog
of the churches that he had made. He had
made so many altars. He had done so many
different altars. He gave ME DIFFERENT
PICTURES. SO MANY DIFFERENT pictures
together with pastor RB and pastor
Dixon. We looked through the many many
options he had and we PICKED THIS ONE.
THE REPUTATION OF THE GUY BECAUSE WAS TO
DO ALTARS AND BECAUSE HE HAS THAT
REPUTATION HE BECAME VALUABLE.
LET YOUR LIGHT SHINE
before men
THAT THEY MAY SEE YOUR GOOD WORKS AND
GLORIFY.
What is it that you are known for?
What is it?
I'm telling you today,
I'm telling you today, whatever you're
doing, even if it's selling chicken, if
you're known for selling good chicken,
you'll be rich.
I'm telling you,
whatever you're known for, if you're
known
being a good mechanic,
people will come TO YOU. WHATEVER IT IS
THAT YOU'RE KNOWN, WHAT IS IT THAT
YOU'RE KNOWN FOR?
What is it that you're known for? You
want to become a person of value and
PEOPLE DON'T KNOW YOU. YOUR LIGHT IS NOT
SHINING BEFORE MEN. How will they even
recognize WHERE YOU ARE? IF YOUR LIGHT
IS NOT SHINING, THEY CAN'T SEE YOU. THEY
TRY TO LOOK FOR YOU. THEY CAN'T SEE YOU.
YOU ARE TOO HIDDEN. YOU ONLY BECOME
VALUABLE WHEN YOUR light
shines
before men. and they begin to look for
that light.
What is it you're known for?
Becoming a person
of value.
The other thing that you know if you're
going to become a person of value
is that you have to be
a person who is
not desperate.
but showing respect.
A big difference.
The Bible says in the book of Proverbs
17 and 27, a man of understanding is of
an excellent spirit.
There's a thin line between respect and
neediness.
Desperate people are begging, forcing
access, trying too hard to impress.
If you're going to be a person of value,
please
value yourself. Look at someone say
value yourself.
Come on, tell them value yourself. Shout
to them. Tell them bishop say that value
yourself. If you come to House of Grace,
I command you to honor yourself and to
value yourself. This business of being
desperate, if somebody does not want to
talk to you, leave them.
I'm not going to beg you. Please, I
honor myself too much. I respect myself
too much. I'm not going to send you a
text in the morning, in the afternoon,
in the evening, and then call you
tomorrow morning, in the morning, in the
afternoon, in the evening. I'm not
desperate. Look at somebody. I'm not
desperate.
Oh, come on. I'm a person of value. AND
YOU CARRY YOURSELF AS A PERSON OF VALUE.
COME ON. SET YOUR STANDARD, SISTER. SET
YOUR STANDARD, MAN. COME ON. ARE YOU
LISTENING TO WHAT I'M SAYING? UH, YOU
WILL NEVER BE A PERSON OF VALUE IF YOU
ARE DESPERATE. YES, I'M GOING TO BE
RESPECTFUL. I'M GOING TO HONOR YOU. BUT
PLEASE, I'M NOT BEGGING TO HAVE ACCESS
TO YOU.
>> WHAT IS THIS BUSINESS?
IF I CALL YOU, YOU DON'T RETURN MY CALL.
FINE. I MARK IT.
Yesterday I met somebody. I had been
introduced to him, you know, uh he works
in this one big office in the government
and I needed something to be done. So I
one year ago.
So I sent him a message,
you know, because when you're being
introduced, it was very cordial.
Oh no, you're fine. Good. N let's get
together. I can do it. All right, I'll
call you tomorrow. Called, he didn't
pick. Send a message. He didn't pick.
That was the end.
That was the end. I met him yesterday
after two years. He couldn't even
remember me somehow.
Somebody who cannot remember Bishop
Morvi, you must you need help in the
psychiatric hospital.
I told him, my friend, how are you?
Good, good, good, good. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
you remember? Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So,
we were with other people. I didn't talk
to him again.
I didn't talk to him again. So, when it
came to his time to leave, he said,
"Bishop, please let me do that thing you
two years ago. I can was it done? Let me
do it. Please. Do you do you have your
ID? Give me your ID now." Said, "Don't
worry. Take it easy. I I'll call you on
Monday."
YEAH. DON'T BE DESPERATE.
>> YOU'RE A PERSON OF VALUE. COME ON, HOUSE
OF GRACE. I WILL HONOR YOU. I WILL
RESPECT YOU. BUT I WILL NOT BE THERE
BEGGING AND LICKING YOUR SHOES, YOU
KNOW, AND OH, COME ON. CLEANING UP YOUR
NOSE SO THAT YOU CAN DO SOME THINGS FOR
ME. I AM NOT DESPERATE. LOOK AT
SOMEBODY. OH, I FEEL LIKE I NEED TO RUN
AWAY FROM THIS CHURCH. TELL THEM I AM
NOT DESPERATE. I'M A PERSON OF VALUE.
>> YOU'RE A PERSON OF VALUE.
>> CARRY YOURSELF LIKE A PERSON OF VALUE.
HALLELUJAH.
>> Reading a book THIS TWO WEEKS AGO AND
THEY were talking ABOUT HOW HOW TO BE
VALUABLE IS JUST EVEN YOUR PRESENCE. YOU
DON'T HAVE TO SAY SOMETHING. JUST
ENTERING A ROOM, THE WAY YOU WALK, THE
WAY YOU TALK, THE WAY YOU LISTEN. OH,
COME ON. IT CREATES VALUE IN YOU. DON'T
BE
YOU WILL BE DISRESPECTED. CARRY YOURSELF
WITH VALUE AND PEOPLE WILL ESTEEM YOU.
AM I TALKING TO SOME PEOPLE IN THIS
CHURCH?
Person of value.
I'll send you a text. Yes.
I'll call you once
and leave it
because you're a person
of value.
A Muslim guy told me, "Scarity
creates value."
Scarcity
creates value.
Don't be too much.
Are you listening to me?
Don't be too much
on people.
Even your Can I say this?
>> Can I really say? Are you sure? People
don't want me to say, so I won't say it.
Only three people said I should say it.
>> Even your text messages should not be
flooding your boyfriend
or your girlfriend.
You send a whole thesis in the morning.
After one hour, you send another thesis.
After another one, you send another. Oh,
God.
Be calculative.
You're a person of value. Whatever you
say has to carry weight.
It has to have meaning.
Don't neutralize yourself by being too
much to availability you know you know
this Muslim guy told me you know he he
sat me down he says okay uh how much is
bread I told him the bread was how much
I guessed me I don't buy bread just
guessed maybe 100 B whatever
I said where can you get it I said I can
get in any kiosk here this kiosk there
written Coca-Cola
can buy there or air can buy bread
there.
He said, "What about gold?"
Oh, it's expensive.
How much is gold? Oh, lots of dollars.
Millions of dollars.
Why is it precious?
Because it is cash.
It is cash. That's why it's important.
It's very very valuable. It is scarce.
Bread is not valuable.
It is available.
Scarcity
creates value.
Are you listening to me? Are you
listening to me?
Say, "Hi." HI. HOW ARE YOU DOING? YOU'RE
DOING WELL. I WAS WAITING FOR YOU TO SAY
HELLO TO ME.
Even if you are waiting,
look at
move with strategy. I'm preaching very
well today. One. Hey, I'm preaching
well.
Yeah.
Create value.
Don't show like
we don't value.
Let me not say
we don't value women that are easily
available.
Can the man say amen?
>> In fact, I'll be suspicious.
Why is she available?
But if you give me a rough time,
can we have tea? No, no, no. I'm busy.
I've got a calendar. And by the way,
never change your calendar for somebody.
That's another point. That's another
point. Are you listening to me? Whether
you're a man or a woman, this is
counseling or what? It's like I'm
counseling you. Whether you're a man or
woman, you never change your appointment
because of a love affair.
coming valuable. I'm valuable.
I'm precious.
All right. The other thing I want to
tell you is if you're going to be
valuable, you have to be open to
learning.
Open to learn. Let me give you the
scripture for that. Because when you
open to learn, it means that you're
improving.
You're doing well.
You are improving yourself.
So
you learn,
you get knowledge.
Lost my notes.
It's in my heart.
You get knowledge. You're improving
yourself. You're moving from glory to
glory, from strength to strength. Iron
sharpens iron. Asking the right
questions,
being there to listen, and particularly
when you're there with people who have
achieved more than you have achieved,
please uh shut your mouth, open your
ears, uh listen to what THEY'RE SAYING,
AND ASK CALCULATIVE QUESTIONS.
Are you listening to me?
Learning.
Learning. And there are many avenues of
learning.
Exposure is learning.
Doesn't have to be in a classroom where
you're seated and the professor is
lecturing you. It doesn't have to be
just that. THAT IS ALSO LEARNING. Uh but
let me tell you, if you go to Japan
today, you will learn something. Uh if
you go to India, you will learn
something. Uh if you go to another
geographical area, you're exposed to
something else. It improves your
learning. Uh so you keep on LEARNING SO
THAT YOU ARE NOT STAGNANT. YOU ARE NOT
STATIONARY. YOU ARE NOT GLUED TO A
PARTICULAR PLACE. UH YOUR KNOWLEDGE IS
MOVING FROM GLORY TO GREATER. Oh come on
somebody LOOK AT SOMEBODY TELL THEM IF
YOU'RE GOING TO BE VALUABLE YOU HAVE TO
KEEP ON LEARNING. STAND UP ON YOUR FEET
AND TELL SOME THREE PEOPLE KEEP
LEARNING. KEEP LEARNING. KEEP LEARNING.
YOU MAY NOT SEE THE NEED FOR WRITTEN
RIGHT NOW, BUT IT WILL COME HANDY. OH,
COME ON, SOMEBODY. IT WILL COME HANDY.
COME ON. COME ON. COME ON. IT WILL COME
HANDY ONE DAY. BUT YOU HAVE TO KEEP ON
LEARNING, KEEP ON IMPROVING, KEEP ON
SCALING THE HEIGHTS. AM I TALKING TO
SOME PEOPLE IN THE HOUSE OF GRACE TODAY?
COME ON, SOMEBODY. CAN SOMEBODY PUT YOUR
HANDS TOGETHER? GIVE JESUS CHRIST A
ROUND OF APPLAUSE.
THE DAY YOU STOP learning
is the day you start dying.
The day
you stop learning
is the day you start
dying.
Brothers and sisters, ladies and
gentlemen,
valuable people are constantly
learning.
Learning
I was told this
and I'm going to tell you
if you move
to where greatness is,
please make sure
you keep your mouth shut. For if you
talk,
you'll only go back with what is in your
head.
Yes,
valuable people
are always
learning
learning the stuff
and never giving up.
Brothers and sisters, the other thing
that you need to do
is
to be a person
who can add value
before you ask.
Add value.
Before you ask,
before you want,
before you want something to be done for
you,
add value
to whoever.
To whoever. Be it in the church, be it
in the place of work.
Add value before you ask. Some of you
are asking more than you're adding.
And the more
you are asking, the more you diminish in
value. Are you listening to me? Last
point I want to give you.
If you're going to be a person of value,
remember
seed time and harvest. Don't be in a
rush. Don't rush it. Remember,
seed time and harvest will always COME
FOR ANYTHING THAT IS rushed out of its
season backfires.
TAKE YOUR TIME.
GO STEADILY
until the time
is ripe. And if you do those things,
you're going to be a valuable
person. There are prophetic declaration
I wanted to give. Can't even find my
notes. I don't know where they went.
The devil is so annoyed with this
sermon.
Find them. But I have them in my heart.
Thank God. I was told when I was in
Bible school, make sure what you write,
it's also in your heart. For your notes
that time, we didn't have this can be
blown with the wind. What will you do?
And you're supposed to be preaching.
Come on, House of Grace. PICK UP
YOURSELF AND GIVE JESUS A ROUND OF
APPLAUSE.
HALLELUJAH.
I want you to declare with open up your
mouth and say, "From today."
>> From today,
>> come on, shout like you really believe.
From today,
>> from today,
>> I realize
>> I'm a person of value.
From today,
>> FROM TODAY,
>> I RESPECT MYSELF.
>> I REFUSE TO BE STUCK.
>> God will be glorified.
>> IN MY LIFE,
>> MY
>> LIGHT WILL SHINE.
>> MY LIGHT
>> AND NO DEVIL WILL QUENCH IT.
>> IN JESUS NAME.
>> AMEN.
>> AMEN. AND AMEN.
HALLELUJAH.
COME ON. Come on. Come on. Come on. Come
on. HOUSE OF GRACE. CELEBRATE THE LORD.
COME ON.
People
are not made
because they want jobs. People
become valuable because they have grown
to a place where they can solve
problems.
Remember that.
Remember that
when you grow to that level
where you can solve problems,
you become a valuable person.
Before you sit down,
give somebody a high five and tell them
I am valuable.
>> Listen, I'm valuable. I'm valuable. I am
val. Amen.
>> Amen. One more time. Give Jesus a round
of applause. We've come to the end of
the song.
Glory. Glory. Glory. Glory. Glory.
Glory.
You have to respect
yourself. Don't be desperate.
Honor whoever needs to be honored,
but don't be desperate. Don't force
access on people
because you're valuable.
There are people I don't call anymore
cuz I don't want to force access. I'm
also valuable. Amen.
And when you look around,
even where you're forcing your excess,
it doesn't mean so much to your life.
At the end of the day,
you eat and you drink without them.
>> You live and walk and have your be in
Jesus without them. Amen.
>> So honor yourself and respect yourself
because you are a valuable individual in
Jesus name.
>> Amen. You may be seated.